Kim Sarabia

Cell: 646-893-9136 hello@kimsarabia.com Portfolio: kimsarabia.com Github: github.com/kimsarabia

Professional Summary

Exceptionally creative and dependable Frontend Developer with diverse career background and ten years of supporting IT, web, and data management in the social sector. Knowledgeable in the JavaScript technology stack as well as the principles and techniques of frontend and backend engineering. Enthusiastic autodidact with a passion for continuous learning and collaborating with teams.

Most Recent Projects

Tech Nation (technation.top) - Proprietary E-commerce web app, providing consumer-to-business sales services

Role: HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS Development, Wireframing

Project Janus (projectjanus.tech) – Open source facial recognition playlist project built with Spotify and Microsoft Oxford APIs

Role: HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS Development Jumpy Jeepney (apple.co/2b0zUw8) – iTunes game Role: GUI Design, Xcode Build and Deployment

Core Qualifications

- Highly proficient writing communication skills
- Professional graphic design and digital illustration experience
- Proficiency in Command Line Interface and UNIX and Mac OS X operating systems
- Strong knowledge of Angular 1.x and exposure to Angular 2, React, and D3
- Excellent grasp of Node.js and Express
- Sound familiarity with using MySQL and Sqlite
- Outstanding knowledge of Bootstrap, Sass, ¡Query, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript
- Solid creative and analytical problem-solving and troubleshooting skills

Experience

Freelance Web Developer and Graphic Designer

January 2015 - Present

Partial Client List: Business IT Advantages, Tag Arcade, RM Myers, June Baby Productions, Colorlines.com, Basatne Electronics USA and International

- Contributed to design and development of client and server database applications
- Maintained and updated HTML5/CSS3 templates on a regular basis and as required
- Assisted in planning and implementing dynamic and online electronic commerce applications
- Conducted layout design and construction for a variety of websites as assigned
- Coordinated with clients to develop engaging and innovative graphic designs for logos, flyers, posters, and page layouts

Director of Development and Digital Community

Brandworkers

June 2015 - November 2015

New York, NY

- Email development, including coding emails using HTML and CSS, with rendering testing across email clients and mobile devices
- Graphic design modification and image creation, deployment, campaign set-up, segmentation, targeting, and A/B testing
- Assisted the Salesforce administrator in troubleshooting and solving problems
- Helped to create new Salesforce applications for a variety of campaigns

Kim Sarabia Resume Page 2

Finance Associate

Race Forward

January 2013 - June 2015

New York, NY

- Managed the Salesforce database for national organization
- Performed basic Salesforce administration, de-duping and cleanup procedures
- Provided support on company supplied hardware and equipment
- Supported Technology Strategist in customer and technology information to determine technical support level
- Performed troubleshooting techniques over the phone or via web messenger to identify and resolve issues
- Automated tasks with Excel through VBA tool

Program Assistant

The New York Immigration Coalition

August 2011 - January 2013

New York, NY

- Created and updated templates of Joomla website
- Utilized Votebuilder software systems to track interaction with potential voters
- Enhanced organization's microtargeting abilities by managing central voter database storing voter information
- Managed, improved, and enhanced online client database essential to legal team

Education

Bachelor's Degree - Political Science

2011

Indiana University

Bloomington, IN

GPA: 3.7

Data Analysis and Statistical Software Training

Graduate - Coding House (Silicon Valley Coding Bootcamp)

Building fullstack applications 80 hours/week for 6 months